polerstuff.com 2018-09-06

# Customer Service – Poler Stuff

## HOW TO RETURN AN ITEM

You can return your unwashed, unworn, brand new Poler Stuff with tags still attached within 30 days for an exchange or refund. If you would like to return your stuff, please contact [customerservice@polerstuff.com ](mailto:customerservice@polerstuff.com)with the following information:

1\. Order # (located on your invoice or in your confirmation email)

2\. Items you would like to return

3\. Your preference for a refund or exchange.

Poler will issue a return authorization form based on the information you provide. We cannot accept items which are returned without the RA form, or are not included in your RA form. We will provide you with a ship label for your return if your order was over $100 and you are located within the Contiguous United States. Any orders placed that total under $100 will not be eligible for free returns. Poler will provide freight for all exchange items shipped back to the customer at no additional cost.

The Fine Print:

Please note that Poler can only offer exchanges for items of equal value or a combination of lesser value product and a partial refund. Poler does not store payment information and cannot charge your original payment method for a more expensive item. Gifts can only be returned for a refund to the original purchaser, an exchange, or store credit. Poler can only accept returns for items purchased through our store or our website. All other returns should be referred to the retailer from whom your Poler Stuff was purchased. Poler cannot exchange full price items for those purchased at a sale price. Poler cannot refund expedited shipping charges. Exchanges can only be fulfilled once the original purchase has been returned to our warehouse. Processing of returns can take up to 5 business days. Refunds issued to your account can require up to 7 days to post. Poler cannot process returns for customers residing outside of the U.S., and all international sales are final.

## Cozy Stuff Care

We've been everywhere in our Cozy Stuff and have had the opportunity to find the best way to freshen them up without causing any damage, fading, or clumping. 

1.) We highly recommend NOT using a washing machine to wash your Napsack/Poncho/Sleeping Sack. We have been met with very poor results in the past (a permanently tangled mess about the size of a basketball). This is dependent on your specific washer and mainly happens with newer High Efficiency washers. You can always use a wash bag to prevent this from happening as well.  

2.) Instead, hand wash in cold water with a light detergent. 

3.) Rinse well, being sure to rinse out all detergent. 

4.) Lay flat to let air dry (not in direct sunlight) OR throw in a dryer on low heat with some dryer balls or tennis balls, just something that won't let the filling clump together. 

5.) Enjoy your clean Stuff! 

## WARRANTY STUFF

Poler Stuff is built with camp vibes, adventuremobiles and excursions in mind. Our Napsacks, Tents, and Bags are fully warrantied with proof of purchase to the original owner against defects in material and workmanship for one year from date of purchase. This warranty does not cover damage caused by accident, improper care, negligence, normal wear and tear, or the natural breakdown of materials over extended time and use. 

If you believe your product has a defect in craftsmanship please contact us at [customerservice@polerstuff.com](mailto:customerservice@polerstuff.com) and reference your Poler order number.  Poler may require the defective merchandise to be returned for a warranty evaluation.

We are unable to offer warranty support for international orders at this time.

## US Shipping Policy

USA Shipping Policy:

Poler proudly offers FREE UPS GROUND SHIPPING for all orders with a subtotal equal to or greater than $100 to contiguous USA destinations. 

Most orders leave our warehouse within 3 to 5 business days.  You will be emailed tracking information once your order ships.

UPS cannot deliver to PO Box addresses and you will be emailed and asked for an alternate address if you enter a PO Box address at checkout. This may delay the processing time of your order. 

UPS uses a zone system to calculate probable shipping time (see map below).  Estimated shipping times are listed in business days.  Neither Poler nor UPS guarantees arrival dates for UPS ground shipments.

**Expedited Shipping:**  Please understand our warehouse requires time to process your order for shipping.  Once processed, shipping time begins from the date of UPS pickup, i.e. orders placed with 2nd-day service will still require 1-2 business days processing time in addition to the shipping time indicated by the expedited service tier.

Please take a moment to review the UPS shipping zone map, and make sure you select the service which is appropriate for your needs.  If you have any questions regarding the shipping time for your package, please contact Poler Customer Service via email at:  [customerservice@polerstuff.com](mailto:customerservice@polerstuff.com) 

## International Shipping Policy

Your country may require you to pay import fees, customs, duties and value added taxes (VAT), etc. which is not included in the price and shipping cost listed on our website. These charges are the sole responsibility of the customer.

Poler will not replace or offer refunds for orders which are abandoned due to non-payment of taxes and fees required by your country.

Orders leave our warehouse between 3-5 business days, however during the holiday season order processing time may take 7-10 business days for in-stock merchandise. During this processing time, your order is safely packed, and processed for shipment as quickly as possible. Due to our short processing time we will not be able to make any changes once your order has been placed.  Once your order is processed you will receive an email confirmation. You will be emailed tracking information once your order leaves our warehouse.

Need your Poler Outdoor Stuff fast? Please choose one of our expedited shipping options to ensure prompt delivery to meet your needs.  **Orders placed by  9 a.m. Pacific Standard Time will ship the same business day. Expedited orders placed after this time will be shipped the following business day.**

We want to ensure that your order is shipped to you as quickly as possible. If you believe that your order has experienced a delay in shipment that exceeds the normal processing and shipment time, please let us know us by email at [customerservice@polerstuff.com](mailto:customerservice@polerstuff.com)

Poler can not at this time ship to a P.O. Box.

****All international sales are final****

## Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

Effective date: May 25, 2018

Poler LLC ("us", "we", or "our") operates the https://www.polerstuff.com/ website (the "Service").

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible from https://www.polerstuff.com/

Definitions

**Service**

Service is the https://www.polerstuff.com/ website operated by Poler LLC

**Personal Data**

Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).

**Usage Data**

Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

**Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on your device (computer or mobile device).

**Data Controller**

Data Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal information are, or are to be, processed.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data.

**Data Processors (or Service Providers)**

Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

**Data Subject (or User)**

Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Service and is the subject of Personal Data.

Information Collection and Use

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

Types of Data CollectedPersonal Data

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Data"). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

Email addressFirst name and last namePhone numberAddress, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, CityCookies and Usage Data

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send.

Usage Data

We may also collect information how the Service is accessed and used ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

Tracking Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

**Session Cookies.**  We use Session Cookies to operate our Service. **Preference Cookies.**  We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings. **Security Cookies.**  We use Security Cookies for security purposes.Use of Data

Poler LLC uses the collected data for various purposes:

To provide and maintain our ServiceTo notify you about changes to our ServiceTo allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do soTo provide customer supportTo gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our ServiceTo monitor the usage of our ServiceTo detect, prevent and address technical issuesTo provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such informationLegal Basis for Processing Personal Data Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), Poler LLC legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Data we collect and the specific context in which we collect it.

Poler LLC may process your Personal Data because:

We need to perform a contract with youYou have given us permission to do soThe processing is in our legitimate interests and it's not overridden by your rightsFor payment processing purposesTo comply with the lawRetention of Data

Poler LLC will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

Poler LLC will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.

Transfer of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Poler LLC will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

Disclosure of DataBusiness Transaction

If Poler LLC is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your Personal Data may be transferred. We will provide notice before your Personal Data is transferred and becomes subject to a different Privacy Policy.

Disclosure for Law Enforcement

Under certain circumstances, Poler LLC may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

Legal Requirements

Poler LLC may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

To comply with a legal obligationTo protect and defend the rights or property of Poler LLCTo prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the ServiceTo protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the publicTo protect against legal liabilitySecurity of Data

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

"Do Not Track" Signals

We do not support Do Not Track ("DNT"). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. Poler LLC aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

**The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you.**  Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you.

**The right of rectification.**  You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.

**The right to object.**  You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data.

**The right of restriction.**  You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.

**The right to data portability.**  You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format.

**The right to withdraw consent.**  You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where Poler LLC relied on your consent to process your personal information.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).

Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service ("Service Providers"), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

**Google Analytics**

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy Terms web page: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

Behavioral Remarketing

Poler LLC uses remarketing services to advertise on third party websites to you after you visited our Service. We and our third-party vendors use cookies to inform, optimize and serve ads based on your past visits to our Service.

**Google AdWords**

Google AdWords remarketing service is provided by Google Inc.

You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize the Google Display Network ads by visiting the Google Ads Settings page: <http://www.google.com/settings/ads>

Google also recommends installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on - <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> \- for your web browser. Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on provides visitors with the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy Terms web page: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

**Facebook**

Facebook remarketing service is provided by Facebook Inc.

You can learn more about interest-based advertising from Facebook by visiting this page: <https://www.facebook.com/help/164968693837950>

To opt-out from Facebook's interest-based ads follow these instructions from Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217>

Facebook adheres to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising established by the Digital Advertising Alliance. You can also opt-out from Facebook and other participating companies through the Digital Advertising Alliance in the USA <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>, the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada in Canada <http://youradchoices.ca/> or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance in Europe <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>, or opt-out using your mobile device settings.

For more information on the privacy practices of Facebook, please visit Facebook's Data Policy: <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>

**Pinterest**

Pinterest remarketing service is provided by Pinterest Inc.

You can opt-out from Pinterest's interest-based ads by enabling the "Do Not Track" functionality of your web browser or by following Pinterest instructions: <http://help.pinterest.com/en/articles/personalization-and-data>

You can learn more about the privacy practices and policies of Pinterest by visiting their Privacy Policy page: <https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy>

Payments

We may provide paid products and/or services within the Service. In that case, we use third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors).

We will not store or collect your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, Mastercard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information.

The payment processors we work with are:

**PayPal or Braintree**

Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at <https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>

**Authorize.net**

Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at <https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/>

Links to Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

Children's Privacy

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 ("Children").

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective and update the "effective date" at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

By email: customerservice@polerstuff.com

## Contact Us

Have a general question about our products? Or just want to say hi? The best way to get in touch with us is through email at [CustomerService@PolerStuff.com](mailto:customerservice@polerstuff.com?Subject=Hello).

*During the Holidays it may take us a little longer to respond to your emails, please allow a 24 hour response time before reaching out again. Be assured we will get back to you as soon as we can!

For marketing inquiries, please email our team at Marketing@PolerStuff.com
